Guide to the Kurt Seligmann Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- December 1997 Acquisition, 1930-1980; 4; 2.42; (3 boxes)
  - Correspondence, 1937-1959
    - Unsorted correspondence: includes correspondence with Sidney Janis, Julien Levy Gallery, Museum of Modern Art (New York), and Pierre Matisse Gallery, 1941-1942 (Box 30)
    - Artists correspondence: includes correspondence with Alexander Calder, Jean Dubuffet, Paul Goodman, František Kupka, Amédée Ozenfant, Ned Rorem, and Marguerite Yourcenar, 1940-1949; 3 (Box 30)
    - Artists correspondence: includes correspondence with Josef Albers, Pane Barlin, Charles Cajori, Mercedes Carles, Marc Chagall, Katherine Dreier, Esteban Francés, George Grosz, Stanley William Hayter, Jean Hélion, Fernand Léger, and László Moholy-Nagy, 1941-1960 (Box 30)
    - Artists correspondence: includes postcards from Alexander Calder, Marc Chagall, Fernand Léger, and Amédée Ozenfant, 1941-1953 (Box 30)
    - Book acquisitions, 1940-1942; undated (Box 30)
    - Bouchard, Tom and Diana, 1958 (Box 30)
    - Breton, André, 1939-1941, undated; 2 (Box 30)
    - Calas, Nicholas, 1949-1958; 2 (Box 30)
    - Collet, Jean Paul, 1949-1950 (Box 30)
    - Courthion, Pierre, 1941-1960 (Box 30)
    - Donati, Enrico; Georges Duthuit and David Hare, 1949-1953 (Box 30)
    - Duits, Charles, 1950-1954 (Box 30)
    - Earle Ludgin & Company, 1940-1957, undated (Box 30)
    - Flaherty, Monica, 1941-1942, undated (Box 30)
    - Ford, Matta and Orslow, 1940, undated (Box 30)
    - D'Arcy Gallery, 1961 (Box 30)
    - Durlacher Brothers, 1943-1958; 2 (Box 30)
    - White, Ruth, 1942-1961, undated (Box 30)
    - Grierson, Ivy, 1942-1951 (Box 30)
    - Guggenheim, Peggy, undated; 2 (Box 30)
    - Janis, Sidney and Harriet (empty folder), undated (Box 30)
    - Levy, Julien, undated (Box 30)
    - Correspondence regarding Kurt Seligmann's exhibition in Mexico, 1943-1944, undated (Box 30)
    - Mabille, Pierre, 1940-1955, undated (Box 30)
    - Man Ray, 1951, undated (Box 30)
    - Masson, André, undated (Box 30)
    - Mills, Clark, 1941-1942 (Box 30)
    - Murray, Peggy, 1942-1944, undated (Box 30)
    - Museum correspondence, circa 1942-1944 (Box 30)
    - Myers, John, 1949, undated (Box 30)
    - Motherwell, Robert & Reis, Barbara, 1941-1942, undated; 2 (Box 30)
    - Okamoto, Taro, 1952-1953, undated (Box 30)
    - Office of War Information, 1943, undated (Box 30)
    - Ozenfant, Amédée, 1939-1956 (Box 30)
    - Paalen, Wolfgang, 1939-1953, undated (Box 30)
    - Papadaki, S. J., 1943, undated (Box 30)
    - Pemberton, Murdock, 1941, undated (Box 30)
    - Pennsylvania State University, 1957-1959, undated (Box 30)
    - Péret, Benjamin and Remedios Varo, 1942-1955, undated; 3 (Box 30)
    - Raphael, Max, 1941-1952 (Box 31)
    - Reiss family, 1941-1942, undated (Box 31)
    - Richter, Hans & Roditi, Edouard, 1941, undated (Box 31)
    - Rogers, Harold, 1941-1943, undated (Box 31)
    - Sanes, Martin, 1941-1956 (Box 31)
    - Schapiro, Meyer, 1941-1949, undated (Box 31)
    - Tanguy, Yves, 1937-1951; 2 (Box 31)
    - Tchelitchew, Pavel & Goll, Ivan, circa 1941-1951 (Box 31)
    - Tyler, Parker, 1948-1952, undated (Box 31)
    - View & Charles Henri Ford, 1940-1941, undated (Box 31)
    - Unsorted correspondence: includes correspondence with Walter Grab, Ruth Horton, Peter James, Margaret Lowengrund, Henri Pastoureau, and The Tiger's Eye, as well as typescripts and a detailed property report for Kurt Seligmann., 1941-1958 (Box 31)
- December 1997 Acquisition, 1912-1986; 5; 3.25; (10 boxes) + 1 broadside folder
  Contains correspondence, notes, a scrapbook containing artwork, and printed material by or relating to Kurt Seligmann. Includes exhibit catalogs, periodicals and clippings.
  - Scrapbook, 1916 (Box 32)
  - Printed material
    - Allied Chemical Corporation. Notice of Special Meeting of Stockholders To Be Held on February 16, 1962, 1962 January 12 (Box 33)
    - Journal of the Archives of American Art, 1964 July (Box 33)
    - The Art Institute of Chicago Quarterly, 1952 September 15 (Box 33)
      Includes an article by Kurt Seligmann entitled "A Letter About Drawing From Kurt Seligmann."
    - New York City Center of Music and Drama, 1953 (Box 33)
    - Kunsthalle Basel. Neue Kunst in der Schweiz; exhibition including works by Kurt Seligmann, 1938 (Box 33)
    - theARTgallery, 1961 November (Box 33)
      Includes announcement of Kurt Seligmann's exhibition at the D'Arcy Gallery in New York City.
    - Columbia University Art Classes; visiting critic: Kurt Seligmann, circa 1942 (Box 33)
    - Yellow Hammer; Briarcliff Junior College yearbook, 1942 (Box 33)
      Includes presentation inscriptions to Kurt Seligmann, who worked as art instructor at the college.
    - The American Federation of Arts. Extension Services, 1961-1964 (Box 33)
    - Horizon; Vol. XIV, no. 83, 1946 (Box 33)
      Includes reproductions of works by Kurt Seligmann.
    - Carnegie Magazine, 1948 (Box 33)
      Includes Homer Saint Gaudens' article "I Like to Look At It" mentioning briefly Kurt Seligmann.
    - Pictures on Exhibit, 1960-1977 (Box 33)
    - College Art Journal; Vol. XVII, no. 2, 1958 Winter (Box 33)
      Includes reproduction of painting entitled "Christ and The Money-Changers" from the collection of Kurt Seligmann.
    - Exposition Taro Okamoto, 1950s (Box 33)
    - The Azuma, Kabuki Dancers and Musicians; playbill for the Broadway Theatre, 1956 January 9 (Box 33)
    - Playbill; Vol. 4, no. 48, 1960 November 21 (Box 33)
    - Craft Horizons; Vol. XXX, no. 6, 1970 December (Box 33)
      Includes an article by John Berhard Myers entitled "The Puppets of Kurt Seligmann - An Homage."
    - transformation; Vol. 1, no. 2, 1951 (Box 33)
      Includes article by Kurt Seligmann entitled "artist - symbol - society."
    - Dance Observer; Vol. 14, no. 1, 1947 January (Box 33)
      Includes critique of Kurt Seligmann's stage designs for the ballet "The Four Temperaments."
    - 14 rue du Dragon; No. 2, 1933 April (Box 34)
    - artsMagazine; Vol. 60, no. 6, 1986 February (Box 34)
      Includes article by Martica Sawin entitled "Magus, Magic, Magnet: The Archaizing Surrealism of Kurt Seligmann" and a handwritten note from Martica to Arlette Seligmann.
    - Third Tokyo Independent Art Exhibition, 1951 (Box 34)
    - Galerie Paul Facchetti. 10 ans d'activité, 1959 (Box 34)
    - Galerie Paul Facchetti. Zoltan Kemeny; exhibition catalogue, 1959 (Box 34)
    - The Hanover Gallery. Paintings by Gerald Wilde, Italian Studies by Michael Ayrton; exhibition catalogue, 1948 (Box 34)
    - The Hanover Gallery. Paintings by Vuillard and Bonhomme; exhibition catalogue, 1948 (Box 34)
    - Ruzo, Daniel. La culture Masma, 1956 (Box 34)
    - Schapiro, Meyer. "Muscipula Diaboli, The Symbolism of the Mérode Altarpiece", 1945 September (Box 34)
    - Schapiro, Meyer. "The Religious Meaning of the Ruthwell Cross", 1944 December (Box 34)
    - Newspaper clippings, circa 1957-1959 (Box 34)
    - Macchioro, Vittorio. The Villa of the Mysteries in Pompei, undated (Box 34)
    - New York World's Fair (1939-1940: New York, N.Y.). Masterpieces of Art (Box 34)
      Includes original sketches on covers and half-title page.
    - Sculpture by Despiau, 1938 (Box 34)
      Includes photograph of paintings and ink sketches.
    - Führer durch das Museum für Volkerkunde Basel, 1935 (Box 34)
    - abstraction, création, art non figuratif, 1933 (Box 34)
    - Die Kunst; herausgegeben von Richard Muther, undated (Box 34)
    - Gravures contemporaines americaines; exhibition catalogue, 1950 (Box 34)
    - Art Association of Montreal. Catalogue of the Permanent Collections, 1934 (Box 34)
    - Guggenheim-Grünberg, Florence. Die ältesten jüdischen Familien in Lengnau und Endingen, 1954 (Box 34)
    - Guggenheim-Grünberg, Florence. Aus einem alten Endinger Gemeindebuch. Der Schutz- und Schirmbrief für die Judenschaft zu Endingen und Lengnau vom Jahre 1776, 1952 (Box 34)
    - The Argosy Gallery. American Art, undated (Box 34)
    - Robert Elkon Gallery. New Acquisitions, 1969 (Box 35)
      Includes reproduction of untitled painting by Kurt Seligmann.
    - Maitres de demain; exhibition catalogue, 1947 (Box 35)
      Includes original sketches on covers and fly-leaves.
    - Kenzo Okada; exhibition catalogue, 1959 (Box 35)
    - Courbet, 1942 (Box 35)
    - Partisan Review, 1946-1950 (Box 35)
    - Exhibition catalogues of Kurt Seligman, 1960 (Box 35)
    - Stoddard, John L. Rebuilding A Lost Faith, undated (Box 35)
    - Our Lady of Guadalupe, 1951 (Box 35)
    - Philip, L. Brand. "The Peddler by Hieronymus Bosch, a Study in Detection", undated (Box 35)
    - Pearson, Ralph M. Critical Appreciation Course II: The Modern Renaissance in the U.S.A., 1950 (Box 35)
    - Kunstschätze der Lombardei, 1948-1949 (Box 36)
    - Die Kunst und das schőne Heim, undated (Box 36)
    - Kunsthaus Zürich. Kunstschätze der Lombardei, circa 1965 (Box 36)
    - Modern French, 1955 (Box 36)
    - The Wentworth Woodhouse Library, 1951 (Box 36)
    - Minotaure; No. 12-13, undated; 2 (Box 36)
    - Extrait de la Gazette des Beaux-Arts, 1950s; 3 (Box 36)
    - Gazette des Beaux-Arts, 1953 September (Box 36)
    - Bookseller catalogues, circa 1946-1957; 8 (Box 37)
    - Bookseller catalogues, 1944, undated; 2 (Box 38)
    - France - Japon, 1937 (Box 38)
    - Schapiro, Meyer. "From Mozarabic to Romanesque in Silos", 1939 (Box 38)
    - Falk, Ilse & Lányi, Jeno. "The Genesis of Andrea Pisano's Bronze Doors", 1943 (Box 38)
    - The New Yorker, 1954 October 30 (Box 39)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1930s-1950s (Box 39)
    - Courthion, Pierre. "Le sujet et le thème dans les arts plastiques d'aujourd'hui", undated (Box 39)
    - Cornelius Nepos, 1912 (Box 39)
    - Artists Equity Association, brochure, undated (Box 39)
    - Art News, 1943-1962; 7 (Box 39)
    - Robert Elkon Gallery. Twentieth Century Masters; exhibition catalogue, 1971 (Box 39)
    - National-Zeitung Basel, 1951 July 16 (Box 40)
    - New York Times Magazine, 1959 September 27 (Box 40)
    - "Guilde Internationale de la Gravure", undated (Box 40)
    - Art International, 1961 (Box 40)
    - Kunsthalle Bern, 1966 (Box 40)
    - Japanese newspapers, unidentified; 2 (Box 40)
    - Herald Tribune Book Review, 1960 November 20 (Box 40)
    - New York Visitor's Reporter, 1960 November (Box 40)
    - Historical Supplement, Orange County Post, Chester Bulletin, and Florida News, undated (Box 40)
    - New York Times Book Review, 1959-1961 (Box 40)
    - New York Times, 1959 October 6 (Box 40)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1961 (Box 40)
    - Derrière le Mirroir, 1949 April (Box 40)
    - Posters advertising Kurt Seligmann's exhibition at the John Bernard Myers Gallery, 1971 (Box 41 (Broadside))
  - Items removed from books of Kurt Seligmann's library, 1938-1944, undated; 2 (Box 42)
- Printed Material
  - Printed material (Box A)
  - Printed material (Box B)
  - Printed material (Box C)
  - Printed material (Box D)
  - Printed material (Box E)